MICHAEL WILLIAM FINNEGAN

217 9th Ave San Francisco, CA 94118 ♦ (480) 202-5754 ♦ FinneganW.Michael@gmail.com

Professional Summary:

Experienced product manager, business strategist and database manager with over 7 years of proven results in all aspects of the Data and Ecommerce industry: corporate strategy, payments, customer analytics, data modeling, marketing, customer experience, operations, data analysis, and project management.

Professional Experience:

Zenni Optical; San Francisco Area, CA

October 2020 - Present

Product Manager; Data, Analytics and Site Optimization (October 2020- Present)

- Built, hired, trained and managed a companywide business intelligence team centralizing company analytics and KPIs.
- Executed an ETL data migration from Big Query, Oracle, MYSQL and various public APIs to a centralized Snowflake database.
- Created and led app IOS and Android OKRs, tagging, product roadmap, and testing schedule for updates.
- Improved data integrity and analysis by establishing a customer, revenue, and site data models using enhanced data layering methods with JSC and Google Tag Manager.
- Managed analysts and engineers to develop dashboards, data models, analyses and presentations for senior leadership and key stakeholders, identifying customer flows, customer retention, sales, productivity, logistics and consumer archetypes.

Walmart E-Commerce; San Francisco Area, CA

October 2018- October 2020

Associate Omni Channel Merchant; Omni Channel Integration (May 2020- October 2020)

- Leading a ship from store logistics optimization project encompassing >\$100M in revenue across fulfillment nodes aimed at increasing profitability, shipping speed, and reducing carbon emissions.
- Managed cross departmental ETL data transfer across multiple platforms Hadoop, Teradata, and Hive.
- Executed a department wide pick up today and drop ship project for holiday 2020, geared to increase omnichannel experience for customers online and in-store.

Product Specialist II (June 2019 - May 2020)

- Implemented and A/B tested customer POVs by marketing channel improving conversion (+125Bpts), revenue (+54%), time spent (+34%) and ROAS (+16%).
- Managed all department wide search ads work streams sales, client services and reporting.
- Led and launched a pilot to shift distribution channels to maximize profitability by increasing item affinities by 45% resulting in a year over year +200Bpts increase in contribution profit with a 70% increase in GMV
- Extensive experience in financial modeling, planning, and forecasting using linear models accounting for traffic, CVR, marketing, prices, and inventory.
- Analyzed customer and review data leveraging Likert Scales, purchasing patterns and customer demographics to measure brand equity.
- Summarized and reported project results using confluence and PowerPoint for interested parties and executives.

Product Specialist I (October 2018 - June 2019)

- Establish Mathematical and quantitative analytics to solve everyday business development issues in stores and E-commerce.
- Leveraged statistical modeling to determine pricing and inventory decisions.
- Business Analyst for a \$46 Million category, across >400 vendors with supply chains reaching over 5 countries.
- Experienced in leveraging large data sets using SQL, tableau, looker, pivot tables, and advanced Excel formulas.
- Effectively summarize data visually and create reports and dashboards for decisive decision making.

Macy's Inc.; New York, New York

May 2017- October 2018

Global Business Assistant Account Manager (November 2017- October 2018)

- Forged specific GTM plans for Macy's China, Macy's Dubai, Lucky Brand, Hudson's Bay, and Macy's Backstage.
- Created and sourced new brands for Macy's Backstage strategy and integrated the brands within over 25 stores.

Assistant Merchandise Planner (May 2017-November 2017)

- Oversaw a nationwide implementation of in-store product display methods across over 200 Macy's stores.
- Engaged cross functionally with product development, stores, online, marketing, finance, and vendor relations.

Education:

University of Arizona

August 2013 - May 2017

B.A. Economics, Philosophy, Politics, & Law

Emphasis in Economic Development and International Trade

Skills:

 $\mathsf{SQL} \bullet \mathsf{Python} \bullet \mathsf{Adobe} \ \mathsf{Analytics} \bullet \mathsf{Road} \ \mathsf{Map} \ \mathsf{Development} \bullet \mathsf{SFMC} \bullet \mathsf{Google} \ \mathsf{Analytics} \bullet \mathsf{Big} \ \mathsf{Query}$

♦ KPI & OKR Management and Development ♦ Data Studio♦ Looker ♦ Google Ads Manger API ♦ Microsoft Excel ♦

PowerPoint ♦ Python ♦ Tableau ♦ A/B Testing ♦ Pivot Tables ♦ API Calling ♦ Database Management ♦ETL♦ Optimizely ♦ BI

Tools ♦ Splunk ♦ Amplitude ♦ Segment ♦ CDPs ♦ CRM Integration ♦ Forecasting ♦ Demand Planning ♦ Pricing ♦ Modeling ♦

Strategy ♦ Business Analytics ♦ Vendor Management ♦ Advanced Statistics ♦ Google Sheets ♦ Google Slides ♦ Road Map Development